<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic Theme</title>
    <link>https://aarrietac.github.io/academic/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Academic Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Abel Castro</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://aarrietac.github.io/academic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Test Car</title>
      <link>https://aarrietac.github.io/academic/project/vitual-test-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aarrietac.github.io/academic/project/vitual-test-car/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this project, I&amp;rsquo;m developing a virtual test car in python. The multi-body approach is applied. In this model, nine rigid bodies are considered, namely, 4 wheel-tires, 4 knuckles and 1 chassis (see Fig. 1). The equation of motions are obtained using the Jourdain&amp;rsquo;s Principle, also called the method of virtual power. Finally, a set of three differential equations describe the dynamics of the vehicle. The first set is the kinematic equation, here we coupled the time derivative of the generalized coordinates with the generalized velocities. The second set is the dynamic equation, in this step the generalized acceleration are calculated using the generalized forces and moments. The last set of equation is the dynamics of the forces elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this virtual car, we have three kind of suspension systems available, e.g., Double Wishbone, McPherson and Multi-link. The action of the force elements are calculated using the partial derivatives of its recpetives velocities against the generalized coordinates using to describe the suspension system. The lookup tables are employed to describe the force elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In vehicle dynamics, one of the most important phenomena is the tire-road interaction. In a proper vehicle model, the tire need to be modeled according to the application for which the vehicle model is being built. In this project, the Tire Model easy to use, also called TMeasy, is adopted. This model have two main advantages, e.g., accurate results and low time comsuming.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://aarrietac.github.io/academic/img/vehicle.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Multi-body vehicle model&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://aarrietac.github.io/academic/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aarrietac.github.io/academic/home/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;biography&#34;&gt;Biography&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi! My name is Abel and I&amp;rsquo;m from Peru. Using this personal site I would like share my current research as well as some publications in congress and journals.  I&amp;rsquo;m doing my PhD dregee at PUC-Rio in Brazil. The objetive of my thesis is implement a control algorithm that integrate the main sub-controls that a passenger vehicle have, for instance, ABS, ESP, TCS, etc. My research interest include multibody dynamics, control theory and parallel computing. Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m working at the Mehrkörperdynamik Labor at OTH Regensburg in Germany. Here, my main task is improve a virtual test car model implemented in MATLAB.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design an integrate vehicle control based-on hierarchical architecture for improve the performance of ground vehicles</title>
      <link>https://aarrietac.github.io/academic/publication/cobem_2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aarrietac.github.io/academic/publication/cobem_2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A method to estimate parameters of longitudinal and lateral dynamics of ground vehicles</title>
      <link>https://aarrietac.github.io/academic/publication/cobem_2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aarrietac.github.io/academic/publication/cobem_2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimation of Dynamic Parameters of Ground Vehicles based on Genetic Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://aarrietac.github.io/academic/publication/sae_2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aarrietac.github.io/academic/publication/sae_2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>