<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Academic Theme</title>
    <link>https://aarrietac.github.io/academic/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Academic Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Abel Castro</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://aarrietac.github.io/academic/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Test Car</title>
      <link>https://aarrietac.github.io/academic/project/vitual-test-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aarrietac.github.io/academic/project/vitual-test-car/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;vehicle-modeling&#34;&gt;Vehicle modeling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, I&amp;rsquo;m developing a virtual test car. For the modeling, the multi-body approach is applied and nine rigid bodies are considered, namely, 4 wheel-tires, 4 knuckles and 1 chassis (see Fig. 1). The equation of motions are obtained using the Jourdain&amp;rsquo;s Principle, also called the method of virtual power. Finally, a set of three differential equations describe the dynamics of the vehicle. The first set is the kinematic equation, here, the time derivative of the generalized coordinates is calculated using the kinematic matrix and vector of generalized velocities. The second set is the dynamic equation, in this step the generalized acceleration are calculated using the generalized forces and moments. Finally, with the last set the generalized forces and calculated. In this virtual car, we have three kind of suspension systems available, e.g., Double Wishbone, McPherson and Multi-link. Lookup tables are employed to describe the force elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tire-modeling&#34;&gt;Tire modeling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In vehicle dynamics, one of the most important phenomena is the tire-road interaction. In a proper vehicle model, the tire need to be modeled according to the application for which the vehicle model is being built. In this project, the Tire Model easy to use, also called TMeasy, is adopted. This model have two main advantages, e.g., accurate results and low time comsuming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;note&#34;&gt;Note&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details about this project are available soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>